A Guide to the Charles E. Culpeper Foundation, Inc. records FA025
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Accession 2, 1875, 1878, 1916-2001 1969-2001; 2; 28 Cubic Feet
  - Administration, 1942, 1977, 1980-1998; 1
    - Board of Directors, 1977, 1988-1993; 1
      - Board of Directors Meetings, April 17, 1991 (Reel 1, Frame 764)
      - Board of Directors Meetings, June 26, 1991 (Reel 1, Frame 783)
      - Board of Directors Meetings, October 8, 1991 (Reel 1, Frame 799)
      - Board of Directors Meetings, December 10, 1991 (Reel 1, Frame 813)
      - Board of Directors Meetings, April 15, 1992 (Reel 1, Frame 836)
      - Board of Directors Meetings, June 15, 1992 (Reel 1, Frame 865)
      - Board of Directors Meetings, December 2, 1992 (Reel 1, Frame 897)
      - Board of Directors Meetings - Special Directors Meeting, Colonial Williamsburg - Part I, December 1, 1992 (Reel 1, Frame 965)
      - Board of Directors Meetings - Special Directors Meeting, Colonial Williamsburg - Part II, December 1, 1992 (Reel 2, Frame 1)
      - Board of Directors Meetings, April 6, 1993 (Reel 2, Frame 147)
      - Board of Directors Meetings, June 30, 1993 (Reel 2, Frame 190)
      - Board of Directors Meetings, September 16, 1993 (Reel 2, Frame 254)
      - Board of Directors Meetings, December 14, 1993 (Reel 2, Frame 281)
    - Board of Trustees, 1942, 1994-1998; 2
      This subseries includes grant proposals, schedules of appropriation and payments regarding grant distributions, President's Grants, discretionary grants, and grants made pursuant to Board approval. Meeting hand-out material, which is located at the end of the meeting material, includes the meeting agenda, meeting minutes for the previous committee meeting, financial information regarding dollar amounts to be considered for proposals, and budgetary payment scheduling for grants and grant reports. This subseries also includes alphabetical listings in some cases, of declined requests for funding, noted as 'Declined Letters of Inquiry.'
      Series 1.2 is arranged chronologically.
      - Series 1.2 - Administration - Board of Trustees, 1942, 1994-1998, undated (Reel 2, Frame 357)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, June 25, 1942 (Reel 2, Frame 358)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, January 12, 1994 (Reel 2, Frame 368)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, April 5, 1994 (Reel 2, Frame 378)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, June 14, 1994 (Reel 2, Frame 429)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings - Special Meeting, Cornell University, September 13, 1994 (Reel 2, Frame 578)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, September 14, 1994 (Reel 2, Frame 626)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, December 6, 1994 (Reel 2, Frame 658)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, April 13, 1995 (Reel 2, Frame 689)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, June 27, 1995 (Reel 2, Frame 741)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, September 13, 1995 (Reel 2, Frame 811)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, December 5, 1995 (Reel 2, Frame 848)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, April 30, 1996 (Reel 2, Frame 891)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, June 27, 1996 (Reel 2, Frame 926)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, September 11, 1996 (Reel 2, Frame 945)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, December 10, 1996 (Reel 2, Frame 970)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings - Special Trustees Meeting, Tarpon Springs, March 7, 1997 (Reel 3, Frame 1)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, March 8, 1997 (Reel 3, Frame 36)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, June 25, 1997 (Reel 3, Frame 46)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, September 11, 1997 (Reel 3, Frame 110)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, December 3, 1997 (Reel 3, Frame 125)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, March 25, 1998 (Reel 3, Frame 166)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, June 24, 1998 (Reel 3, Frame 351)
      - Board of Trustees Meetings, October 7, 1998 (Reel 3, Frame 522)
    - Compensation Committee, 1996; 3
      This subseries details personnel and Board of Directors' terms of salary and promotion.
      - Series 1.3 - Administration - Compensation Committee, 1996, undated (Reel 3, Frame 545)
      - Compensation Committee, 1996 (Reel 3, Frame 546)
    - Finance Committee, 1980-1989, 1994-1998; 4
      Only those meetings held between 1994 and 1998 are documented in this subseries. A ten-year history covering the years 1980-1989 is available at the end of this subseries.
      - Series 1.4 - Administration - Finance Committee, 1980-1989, 1994-1998, undated (Reel 3, Frame 548)
      - Finance Committee Meetings - Correspondence, 1994 (Reel 3, Frame 549)
      - Finance Committee Meetings - Correspondence, 1995 (Reel 3, Frame 598)
      - Finance Committee Meetings - Correspondence, 1996 (Reel 3, Frame 725)
      - Finance Committee Meetings - Correspondence, 1997 (Reel 3, Frame 761)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, May 17, 1994 (Reel 3, Frame 865)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, July 26, 1994 (Reel 3, Frame 873)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, October 25, 1994 (Reel 3, Frame 882)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, March 31, 1995 (Reel 3, Frame 897)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, June 13, 1995 (Reel 3, Frame 911)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, August 29, 1995 (Reel 3, Frame 917)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, November 14, 1995 (Reel 3, Frame 924)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, March 13, 1996 (Reel 3, Frame 931)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, June 12, 1996 (Reel 3, Frame 938)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, August 28, 1996 (Reel 3, Frame 1062)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, November 13, 1996 (Reel 3, Frame 1070)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, March 8, 1997 (Reel 3, Frame 1085)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, June 11, 1997 (Reel 3, Frame 1270)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, September 4, 1997 (Reel 3, Frame 1277)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, November 12, 1997 (Reel 3, Frame 1286)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, March 17, 1998 (Reel 3, Frame 1295)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, May 21, 1998 (Reel 3, Frame 1301)
      - Finance Committee Meetings, September 24, 1998 (Reel 3, Frame 1306)
      - Finance Committee Report - Ten Year History, 1980-1989, undated (Reel 3, Frame 1310)
    - Grants Committee, 1985-1992; 5
      The Grants Committee had the authority to determine grant assignments during this brief period.
      - Series 1.5 - Administration - Grants Committee, 1985-1992 (Reel 4, Frame 1)
      - Grants Committee Meetings - Correspondence, 1989 (Reel 4, Frame 2)
      - Grants Committee Meetings - Correspondence, 1990 (Reel 4, Frame 102)
      - Grants Committee Meetings - Correspondence, 1991 (Reel 4, Frame 130)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, September 25, 1985 (Reel 4, Frame 145)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, December 18, 1985 (Reel 4, Frame 148)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, February 10, 1986 (Reel 4, Frame 150)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, April 3, 1986 (Reel 4, Frame 156)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, February 12, 1987 (Reel 4, Frame 161)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, June 23, 1987 (Reel 4, Frame 165)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, March 30, 1988 (Reel 4, Frame 170)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, August 23, 1988 (Reel 4, Frame 176)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, February 15, 1989 (Reel 4, Frame 200)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, May 9, 1989 (Reel 4, Frame 207)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, September 14, 1989 (Reel 4, Frame 212)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, December 7, 1989 (Reel 4, Frame 216)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, April 11, 1990 (Reel 4, Frame 235)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, June 19, 1990 (Reel 4, Frame 244)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, October 4, 1990 (Reel 4, Frame 249)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, December 4, 1990 (Reel 4, Frame 254)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, June 12, 1991 (Reel 4, Frame 265)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, September 24, 1991 (Reel 4, Frame 273)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, November 19, 1991 (Reel 4, Frame 278)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, March 31, 1992 (Reel 4, Frame 286)
      - Grants Committee Meetings, June 15, 1992 (Reel 4, Frame 293)
    - Grants Committee and Board of Directors, 1989-1993; 6
      Meetings were held jointly to include both Grants Committee members and the Board of Directors.
      - Series 1.6 - Administration - Grants Committee and Board of Directors, 1989-1993 (Reel 4, Frame 298)
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, February 15, 1989 (Reel 4, Frame 299)
        Grant proposals were reviewed for the following institutions:
        Brookings Institution Goodspeed Operation House Human Resources Center Salk Institute Widener University
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, May 9, 1989 (Reel 4, Frame 331)
        Ackerman Institute for Family Therapy Alvio Medical Center Bermuda Biological Station for Research College of Mount St. Vincent St. Francis Hospital Simmons College Stamford Hospital Vanderbilt University
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, September 14, 1989 (Reel 4, Frame 381)
        Albert Einstein College of Medicine Beth Israel Medical Center The Conservation Fund Dance Theatre of Harlem Duke University The Foundation Center Hartford Hospital Hospital for Special Surgery Mount Holyoke College National Theater Workshop of the Handicapped New England Association of Schools and Colleges New York Hospital - Cornell Medical Center Rockefeller University Supreme Court Historical Society Union College
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, December 7, 1989 (Reel 4, Frame 492)
        Administrative Conference of the United States American Symphony Orchestra League, Inc. Association of the Bar of the City of New York Bard College BOYS HOPE Brooklyn Botanic Garden California Judges Association Carleton College Carnegie Hall Children's Specialized Hospital Foundation Critical Languages and Area Studies Consortium Dartmouth Medical School Flowers With Care Youth Services Founding Father Papers, Inc. Grinnell College Illinois Benedictine College Lake Forest College Manhattan Eye, Ear and Throat Hospital Metropolitan Museum of Art New York State Judicial Committee on Minorities Paul H. Nitze School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS) Portland School of Art United Negro College Fund University of Cincinnati Medical Center University of Scranton
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, April 11, 1990 (Reel 4, Frame 630)
        Albion College Bellefaire Consortium for Language Teaching and Learning Critical Languages and Area Studies Consortium Friends of Franklin Medical College of Wisconsin National Audubon Society Occidental College Regis College Seattle Opera Association University of Scranton Vivian Beaumont Theatre, Lincoln Center Theater Whitman College
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, June 19, 1990 (Reel 4, Frame 752)
        Academy for Educational Development Connecticut Junior Republic Henry Street Settlement Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine Metropolitan Opera Association Pace University Patrick Henry Memorial Foundation Vanderbilt University Young Audiences, Inc.
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, October 4, 1990 (Reel 4, Frame 830)
        Ackerman Institute for Family Therapy Alfred University Ballet Theatre Foundation Brigham and Women's Hospital Brown University, Center for Neural Science Brown University, Educational Clarke College Colgate University Lahey Clinic Foundation Loyola/Notre Dame Library Messiah College National Building Museum Pension Building National Council of Educational Opportunity Associations Norwich University Roger Williams College Southern Methodist University Student Conservation Association Supreme Court Historical Society Wadsworth Anthenaeum
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, December 4, 1990 (Reel 4, Frame 982)
        Babson College The Conservation Fund Critical Languages and Area Studies Consortium Family Service America Gordon-Conwell Theological Seminary New York Zoological Society Smith College Trinity University Toynbee Prize Foundation, Inc. University of Maine University of Wisconsin WETA Foundation Whittier Institute for Diabetes & Endocrinology
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, June 12, 1991 (Reel 4, Frame 1116)
        Houston Grand Opera Massachusetts General Hospital Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center Middlebury College Nebraska Wesleyan University New York Botanical Garden Orchestra of St. Luke's St. Olaf College Southeastern Wisconsin Information Technology Exchange Studio Museum in Harlem, Inc.
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, September 24, 1991 (Reel 5, Frame 1)
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, November 19, 1991 (Reel 5, Frame 81)
        Carnegie Mellon University Connecticut Players Foundation/Long Wharf Theatre Hood College National Public Radio, Inc. Stamford Center for the Arts University of Chicago
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, March 31, 1992 (Reel 5, Frame 187)
        Carnegie Hall Society, Inc. College of the Holy Cross Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons Johns Hopkins University Lehigh University University of Notre Dame Williams College Yale University School of Medicine
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, June 15, 1992 (Reel 5, Frame 336)
        Dartmouth College Dillard University Franklin & Marshall College Millsaps College New England Board of Higher Education
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, December 2, 1992 (Reel 5, Frame 987)
        Amherst College Betances Health Unit, Inc. Duke University International Bone Marrow Transplant Registry New York Medical College Northeast Document Conservation Center University of Richmond
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings I, April 6, 1993 (Reel 5, Frame 517)
        American Symphony Orchestra, Inc. Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Commission on Preservation and Access Connecticut Grand Opera and Orchestra Critical Languages and Area Studies Consortium Lincoln Center Institute Macalester College Meharry Medical College Mount Holyoke College National Actors Theatre New York Botanical Garden New York City Ballet Sta-Fed ADR, Inc.
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings II, April 6, 1993 (Reel 5, Frame 616)
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, June 30, 1993 (Reel 5, Frame 726)
        Bard College Brooklyn Academy of Music Brown University Consortium for Language Teaching and Learning Cornell University Environmental Careers Organization Henry Street Settlement Northwestern University Pennsylvania Ballet Vivian Beaumont Theatre, Lincoln Center Theater
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, September 16, 1993 (Reel 5, Frame 871)
        Five Colleges Inc. Mountain College Library Network New York Landmarks Conservancy Princeton University Whitney Museum of American Art
      - Grants Committee and Board of Directors Meetings, December 14, 1993 (Reel 5, Frame 955)
        Drew University Massachusetts General Hospital Oberlin College Washington & Lee University
    - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees, 1994-1998; 7
      The joint meetings of the Grants Committee and Board of Trustees are documented for a four-year period.
      Series 1.7 is arranged chronologically.
      - Series 1.7 - Administration - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees, 1994-1998, undated (Reel 5, Frame 1024)
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings I, April 5, 1994 (Reel 5, Frame 1025)
        American Symphony Orchestra, Inc. Arena Stage Case Western Reserve University Center for Contemporary Arts of Santa Fe Fairfield University Gallaudet University Greenwich Hospital Heritage College National Council on Crime and Delinquency, Inc. Roundabout Theatre Company, Inc. Southern Methodist University Tufts University University of Michigan University of Rochester University of Virginia Law School Foundation
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings II, April 5, 1994 (Reel 5, Frame 1166)
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings, June 14, 1994 (Reel 6, Frame 1)
        Alvin Ailey American Dance Theatre Georgetown University Horace Bushnell Memorial Hall Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center National Public Radio, Inc. Princeton University University of Hartford
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings, September 14, 1994 (Reel 6, Frame 165)
        Haverford College Museum of Modern Art New York Public Library for Performing Arts Orchestra of St. Luke's Stamford Hospital Stanford University United Negro College Fund University of Notre Dame Virginia Union University
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings, December 6, 1994 (Reel 6, Frame 353)
        American Inns of Court Bethesda Hospital Association, Inc. Clark University Connecticut Legal Services The Foundation Center Foundation Center Harvard University Meet the Composer Meharry Medical College Smith College University of Massachusetts
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings I, April 13, 1995 (Reel 6, Frame 550)
        Beth Israel Medical Center Connecticut Grand Opera and Orchestra Hamilton College Hartwick College Medical College of Pennsylvania & Hahnemann University Museum of Fine Arts, Houston National Actors Theatre Pacific Lutheran University University of Missouri University of Washington Vivian Beaumont Theatre, Lincoln Center Theater Washington University - St. Louis William Marsh Rice University
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings II, April 13, 1995 (Reel 6, Frame 688)
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings I, June 27, 1995 (Reel 6, Frame 819)
        Bennington College Carleton College Gustavus Adolphus College Illinois Wesleyan University National Academy of Sciences National Building Museum Pension Building New York City Ballet New York City Opera New York Landmarks Conservancy Northwestern University Roundabout Theatre Company, Inc. Scripps College Spanish Theatre Repertory Company Ltd.
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings II, June 27, 1995 (Reel 6, Frame 932)
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings I, September 13, 1995 (Reel 6, Frame 1059)
        American Craft Museum Association of Governing Boards of Universities and Colleges Carnegie Hall Society, Inc. Dallas Theatre Center Dana Farber, Inc. The Governance Institute Metropolitan Opera Association Old State House Association, Inc. University of California, Los Angeles Wadsworth Anthenaeum
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings II, September 13, 1995 (Reel 6, Frame 1174)
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings I, December 5, 1995 (Reel 7, Frame 1)
        Acadia Institute The Folger Shakespeare Library - Amherst College The Governance Institute Kalamazoo College Marymount College National Museum for Women in the Arts New England Board of Higher Education South End Medical Center, Inc. Swarthmore College Trinity College Washington College
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings II, December 5, 1995 (Reel 7, Frame 151)
        Acadia Institute The Folger Shakespear Library - Amherst College The Governance Institute Kalamazoo College Marymount College National Museum for Women in the Arts New England Board of Higher Education South End Medical Center, Inc. Swarthmore College Trinity College Washington College
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings I, April 30, 1996 (Reel 7, Frame 321)
        Allegheny College ArtsConnection Baltimore Symphony Orchestra, Inc. Cedars-Sinai Medical Center Concordia College Eastern Virginia Medical School of the Medical College of Hampton Roads Loyola University, Chicago Strawbery Banke, Inc. Washington Performing Arts Society
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings II, April 30, 1996 (Reel 7, Frame 442)
        Allegheny College Arts Connection Baltimore Symphony Orchestra, Inc. Cedars-Sinai Medical Center Concordia College Eastern Virginia Medical School of the Medical College of Hampton Roads Loyola University, Chicago Strawbery Banke, Inc. Washington Performing Arts Society
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings, June 27, 1996 (Reel 7, Frame 588)
        Brandeis University Colonial Williamsburg Foundation Dallas Opera Georgetown University Teachers and Writers Collaborative, Inc. University of Michigan Wesleyan University
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings, September 11, 1996 (Reel 7, Frame 778)
        Claremont University Center Hartford Stage Company, Inc. Whitney Museum of American Art
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings I, December 10, 1996 (Reel 7, Frame 901)
        American Indian Higher Education Consortium Appalachian College Association, Inc. Arena Stage Clark University Connecticut College Emory University Furman University Hollins College Houston Grand Opera Museum of the City of New York National Gallery of Art New York Academy of Medicine North Dakota Hospital Research and Education Foundation, Inc. Reed College Tobey Hospital Wheaton College
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings II, December 10, 1996 (Reel 7, Frame 1074)
        American Indian Higher Education Consortium Appalachian College Association, Inc. Arena Stage Clark University Connecticut College Emory University Furman University Hollings College Houston Grant Opera Museum of the City of New York National Gallery of Art New York Academy of Medicine North Dakota Hospital Research and Education Foundation, Inc. Reed College Tobey Hospital Wheaton College
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings, June 25, 1997 (Reel 8, Frame 1)
        Corcoran Gallery of Art Jacob's Pillow Dance Festival, Inc. Lynchburg College Southwestern University Trinity University University of Washington
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings, September 11, 1997 (Reel 8, Frame 179)
        American Symphony Orchestra, Inc. Colorado College Dance Theatre Workshop, Inc. Dancing in the Streets, Inc. Lawrence University New York Historical Society RAND Corporation University of Buffalo Foundation, Inc. University of Pennsylvania
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings I, December 3, 1997 (Reel 8, Frame 398)
        American Federation for Clinical Research Foundation American Indian Higher Education Consortium Colleges of the Seneca, Hobart and William Smith Colleges George Washington University Medical College of Wisconsin Mount St. Mary's College New York Blood Center, Inc. Oglethorpe University, Inc. Pomona College Smith College Tufts University UCI Foundation, University of California, Irvine University of Michigan University of Montana University of Pennsylvania Wofford College
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings II, December 3, 1997 (Reel 8, Frame 558)
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings, March 25, 1998 (Reel 8, Frame 843)
        Amherst College Austin College Baystate Medical Center, Inc. Grinnell College Health Research, Inc. Helen Hayes Hospital The New Museum United Negro College Fund Vivian Beaumont Theatre, Lincoln Center Theater
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings, June 24, 1998 (Reel 8, Frame 1039)
        Bennington College Bonfils Blood Center Foundation Brooklyn Academy of Music The College of William and Mary Roundabout Theatre Company, Inc. Tulane University UBW, Inc. (Urban Bush Women)
      - Grants Committee and Board of Trustees Meetings I, October 7, 1998 (Reel 9, Frame 1)